# John Ferro

Web Developer

#### **SUMMARY**

Web developer with 15 years' experience of front-end and back-end coding. Has held a variety of roles including digital marketing producer and digital consultant. Writes clear concise code, communicates well with technical and non-technical people. Is known for patience, persistence, and sense of humor.

**EXPERIENCE** 

## Web Developer

#### J&D Tech Solutions - Minneapolis, MN 2017-2021

Completed short term front-end & back-end assignments as a freelancer. Acted as content manager, archivist, and digital consultant for several clients.

Project Highlight - PeterOstroushko.com: Recovered expired domain and set up a new web site on a new hosting platform. Designed and built bootstrap based site for frequently updated content. Trained users to use third party marketing platforms for email promotions.

## Web Lead

#### MechoShade - Long Island City, NY 2011-2016

Under the supervision of the Marketing Director, led a team of writers and designers to create digital deliverables such as websites and mass email communications. Key projects included:

Dealer Newsletter: Converted all dealer communication from faxes to email. Coded HTML template and by using a third-party platform, collected KPI data, modified content and frequency, grew subscriber base by a factor of 3.

Mechoshade.com overhaul: Led a design refresh and code rewrite. Converted ColdFusion elements to PHP that halved page load times. Content changes reduced bounce rate by 50%.

Adwords launch: Created an inexpensive Google adwords campaign and adopted SEO best practices that doubled website traffic and improved the quality of lead generation.

ERP launch: Using XML and CSS edited and branded software elements for Infor SyteLine launch. Coded extensive edits to customer portal interface, training modules, and print invoices to make a branded experience for an off-the-shelf product.

Minneapolis, MN 55419 (516) 965-2434 ionafi@gmail.com

#### **LINKS**



github.com/jonafi



linkedin.com/in/JohnFerro

#### **SKILLS**

## **Core Technologies**

- HTML
- **CSS**
- JavaScript
- MySQL
- PHP

## **New Technologies**

- Node JS
- React
- MongoDB
- **Express**
- BootStrap

## Additional software, libraries, & platforms

- jQuery
- Git
- Photoshop

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Minnesota Coding **Bootcamp** 

Full Stack Web Development September 2020

# Web Developer

# Ernst & Young - New York, NY 2000-2008

Built and maintained digital tools site used by EY's 130,000 employees.

Branding Zone: With a senior developer built and maintained an intranet portal for all marketing related assets using the Lotus Domino platform.

Photo Repository: Built a searchable document database for storing and displaying high-resolution, royalty managed photographs. Used Lotus Notes based interface with heavy HTML and XML customizations.

Email signature tool: Conceived of and coded a web-based microsite to standardize email signatures. Using only an HTML form and vanilla JavaScript, users were able to create a signature attachment that adhered to the strict branding guidelines in place.